RG 062:047, Town of East Windsor
East Windsor Records, Inventory of Town of
Connecticut State Library
Town of East Windsor records
1768-1993
Connecticut State Library
East Windsor (Conn.)
30.5 cubic feet
Administrative, court and justice of the peace, military, school, and tax records.
RG062_047
Multiple
Historical Note
The town of East Windsor on the east side of the Connecticut River, originally part of the town of Windsor, was incorporated in May 1768. South Windsor separated from East Windsor in May 1845.
Scope and Content
The records of the town of East Windsor consist of materials divided into seven series - Administrative, Court and Law Enforcement, Military, School, Election, Tax, and Other Records.
Arrangement
Series 1. Administrative Records, 1768-1946 includes treasurer's accounts, Old Age Survivors and Insurance System information, and town orders on the treasurer.
Series 2. Court and Law Enforcement Records, 1854-1973 includes probate records and police patrol records.
Series 3. Military Records, 1852-1883 includes militia enrollment files.
Series 4. School Records, 1826-1933 includes School Board accounts.
Series 5. Election Records, 1841-1993 includes lists of voters admitted.
Series 6. Tax Records, 1850-1971 includes tax lists, grand lists, polls and rateable estates, and tax collector records.
Series 7. Other Records, 1902-1923 includes material related to the East Windsor Memorial Association.
Index Terms
Alternate creator:
Connecticut. Justice of the Peace (East Windsor)
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- East Windsor; Law enforcement -- Connecticut -- East Windsor; Soldiers -- Connecticut -- East Windsor; Voting registers -- Connecticut -- East Windsor; Tax assessment -- Connecticut -- East Windsor -- Registers; Taxation -- Connecticut -- East Windsor -- Registers; Local taxation -- Connecticut -- East Windsor -- Registers; Property tax -- Connecticut -- East Windsor -- Registers; Justices of the Peace -- Connecticut -- East Windsor
Places:
East Windsor (Conn.) -- Records and correspondence
Occupations:
Town clerks; Justices of the Peace
Document Types:
Administrative records; Civil court records; Military records; School records; Tax records; Voters' lists
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Acquisition Information
The Town of East Windsor records with accession 2006-006 were donated to the Connecticut State Library in September 2005.
Container List
- Series 1. Administrative Records, 1768-1946
  - 2006-006
    - Treasurer's accounts
      - 1893-1909 (Volume Vol. 1)
      - 1909-1924 (Volume Vol. 2)
      - 1924-1936 (Volume Vol. 3)
    - Old Age Survivors and Insurance System, 1937-1946
    - Town orders on the treasurer, 1873-1896
  - T000334
    - Register of earmarks and record of found strays, 1769-1850 (Box Box 1)
    - Dog register, 1899-1907 (Box Box 1)
    - Treasurer's accounts (Box Box 1)
      - 1768-1779, 1 volume (Volume Item 1 (not labeled))
      - 1813-1834, 1 volume (Volume Item 2 (not labeled))
      - Vol. 1, 1834-1872 (Box Box 1)
      - Vol. 2, 1873-1894 (Box Box 1)
    - Tax abatement lists, 1831-1904 (Box Box 2)
- Series 2. Court and Law Enforcement Records, 1854-1973; 2006-006
  - Attachments, 1854-1927
  - Probate records, 1856-1861
  - Police Patrol
    - 1962 April 1-1963 September 20 (Volume Vol. 1)
    - 1963 September 20-1965 April 13 (Volume Vol. 2)
    - 1965 April 14-1966 November 20 (Volume Vol. 3)
    - 1966 November 21-1971 December 31 (Volume Vol. 4)
    - 1972 January 1-1973 May 6 (Volume Vol. 5)
- Series 3. Military Records, 1852-1883
  - 2006-006
    - Militia enrollments
      - 1869-1873 (Volume Vol. 1)
      - 1874-1883 (Volume Vol. 2)
  - T000334
    - Military enrollment records, 1852-1861; 2 volumes (Box Box 1)
- Series 4. School Records, 1826-1933
  - 2006-006
    - School Board accounts
      - 1896-1903 (Volume Vol. 1)
      - 1903-1919 (Volume Vol. 2)
      - 1919-1933 (Volume Vol. 3)
  - T000334
    - Second School Society account and record book, 1826-1856 (Box Box 2)
- Series 5. Election Records, 1841-1993
  - 2006-006
    - Voters admitted
      - 1874-1940 (Volume Vol. 1)
      - 1941-1953 (Volume Vol. 2)
      - 1950-1976 (Volume Vol. 3)
      - 1977-1993 (Volume Vol. 4)
  - T000334
    - List of voters, 1841-1890; 6 volumes
- Series 6. Tax Records, 1850-1971; 2006-006
  - Tax lists, Note: For volumes 1-47, one volume covers the area east of the Scantic River and the second the area west of the Scantic River.
    - 1885 (Volume Vols. 1-2)
    - 1886 (Volume Vols. 3-4)
    - 1887 (Volume Vols. 5-6)
    - 1888 (Volume Vols. 7-8)
    - 1889 (Volume Vols. 9-10)
    - 1890 (Volume Vols. 11-12)
    - 1891 (Volume Vols. 13-14)
    - 1892 (Volume Vols. 15-16)
    - 1893 (Volume Vols. 17-18)
    - 1894 (Volume Vols. 19-20)
    - 1895 (Volume Vols. 21-22)
    - 1896 (Volume Vols. 23-24)
    - 1897 (Volume Vols. 25-26)
    - 1898 (Volume Vols. 27-28)
    - 1899 (Volume Vols. 29-30)
    - 1900 (Volume Vols. 31-32)
    - 1901 (Volume Vols. 33-34)
    - 1902 (Volume Vols. 35-36)
    - 1903 (Volume Vols. 37-38)
    - 1904 (Volume Vols. 39-40)
    - 1905 (Volume Vols. 41-42)
    - 1906 (Volume Vols. 43-44)
    - 1907 (Volume Vols. 44-45)
    - 1908 (Volume Vols. 46-47)
    - A-N, 1909 (Volume Vol. 48)
    - O-Z and non-residents, 1909 (Volume Vol. 49)
    - A-M, 1910 (Volume Vol. 50)
    - N-Z and non-residents, 1910 (Volume Vol. 51)
    - A-N, 1911 (Volume Vol. 52)
    - O-Z and non-residents, 1911 (Volume Vol. 53)
    - A-M, 1912 (Volume Vol. 54)
    - N-Z and non-residents, 1912 (Volume Vol. 55)
    - A-M, 1913 (Volume Vol. 56)
    - N-Z and non-residents, 1913 (Volume Vol. 57)
    - A-N, 1914 (Volume Vol. 58)
    - O-Z and non-residents, 1914 (Volume Vol. 59)
    - A-M, 1915 (Volume Vol. 60)
    - N-Z and non-residents, 1915 (Volume Vol. 61)
  - Grand Lists, 1948-1971; 12 volumes
  - Polls and Rateable Estates, East of Scantic, 1850
  - Tax Collector, West of Scantic, 1895
  - Tax Liens, 1917-1924
- Series 7. Other Records, 1902-1923; 2006-006
  - East Windsor Memorial Association, 1902-1923